the drogram show for Monday, August
11th, 2025. Thank you so much for
joining us. We're here Monday,
Wednesday, Friday, 5:00 pm on YouTube
and Rumble, as well as on audio. Thanks
for everyone for liking, following, and
sharing the show and of course
commenting and throwing in your
questions. And as you guys know, we
always get to as many of them as we
possibly can. Um, John, good to see you.
As
>> good to see you, buddy. And
>> and I'm seeing in the comments that uh
that Barnes & Noble didn't go so great.
Huh. I'm sorry.
>> No, it was kind of a catastrophe. And we
can talk about that later, but that's
okay. Uh you know, I mean, it's like uh
producer Robbie did his best to uh and
and apparently they can't spell the name
Ted in um in Callispel, Montana. They
spelled it with two D's. So that was the
beginning of the trouble. So, you know,
if they can't spell your name, it's like
it's not like Cheers where everyone
knows your name. Here, they can't even
spell your name. But anyway, it was
funny. Lots It's good to see you. Um,
given what's going on in DC, um, you
know, you could be you could be in a
fascist goolog right now. Um, Donald
Trump obviously we'll be talking about
that and the DC police uh nationalizing
the police sending the National Guard
and possibly regular troops into the
streets of the city all because of big
balls. Um, the ex the Epstein story uh
the Epstein Maxwell records are sealed.
We'll talk about what what that means.
I'm I'm absolutely livid about this
story out of Gaza that Israel
deliberately assassinated five
journalists from Al Jeazera on purpose.
Yeah, on purpose.
>> But but there's going to there's going
to be an investigation. So
>> yeah, that always works out so great. On
the other hand, um a you know, so Israel
might be psyched about all the
journalists they're killing, but they
did lose Australia today. Australia
recognized Palestine
>> and possibly New Zealand, which is going
to make a decision in the next couple of
weeks.
>> So all the antipods come together. Uh
and then uh Marine T Marjorie Taylor
Green um she's a hot ticket item, man.
She went from just being worth about
$700,000 to in a very short time she's
suddenly worth $22 million. Obviously
she's just a very very intelligent
business person. We'll talk about that.
Um and then of course Trump's meeting
Putin. Maybe uh Zilinsky might be
invited or might not be. So what shall
we do first?
>> Yeah. Let let's let's get DC out of the
way. I made a decision today when I
heard that Donald Trump was federalizing
the Washington DC police force and
taking over um uh police duties in
Washington with the help of the National
Guard. I decided because I I live three
miles from the White House, I'm going to
go up to every National Guardsman that I
see and I'm going to say, "You should be
ashamed of yourself. If there was ever a
time to stand up and say no, now's the
time. you gutless pigs.
>> So, Donald Trump has gotten it into his
head that crime is out of control.
Actually, he probably hasn't even gotten
it into his head. He's just fake faking
it. Excuse me. DC does not have a crime
problem. Murders are down.
Violent crimes overall are down 37%.
>> That's a lot.
>> A lot. We have no crime problem in
Washington right now. But Trump decided
he's taken it over now. He didn't bother
to inform Mayor Muriel Bowser. He didn't
bother to inform the DC police chief. He
just announced that he's taken it over
and that's it. So I looked this up,
>> which he can do legally.
>> He he absolutely can do for a period of
three days. He can take it over for
three days and then he has to get
congressional authorization. Well, guess
what? Congress isn't in session.
And so remember, they all ran away so
they wouldn't have to vote on the
Epstein release.
>> Hilarious.
>> I wonder if they didn't check that.
>> I suspect they didn't check it. And so
this is a publicity stunt. Literally
nothing is going to come of it.
>> Um there's, you know, at the very same
time that he's sending hundreds of
troops to DC to uh patrol the main
streets. And look, I mean, I want to
push back a little bit, John. I mean, DC
has some sketchy parts of town that are
real
>> pit and and the homeless problem is out
of control.
>> And and I'm glad you brought that up
because he says that he is going to
sweep the homeless off the streets. No
word on what that means or where you
going to send them. You going to send
him in Maryland?
>> Yeah. I don't know. It doesn't make any
sense. And then um he also and and then
there's also the story out of Los
Angeles. There's a court hearing right
now even as we speak um about uh the
previous time the few weeks ago when
Trump sent troops there to LA to ICE in
uh mass deportations you know keeping uh
the home the homeland the Home Depot
parking lot safe for democracy
>> right
>> that you know and that looks like uh
very likely that the judge is going to
rule that that act was illegal um and
you know federalizing the California
National Guard but obviously Trump has a
lot more control over
>> over over DC at least as you said
>> for three days by declaring an
emergency. I mean, I kind of hate all
the laws that allow uh elected officials
uh to declare kind of vaguely stated,
vaguely justified emergencies just
because.
>> Yeah, just because. There was a
complaint from a a Republican
congressman uh from New Jersey about
this tent that is set up directly across
the street from the White House at the
edge of Lafayette Square. And it's a
it's a pro Palestine, you know, pro-
nuclear disarmament
kind of ongoing long-term protest. Tell
you the truth, there have been tents
there since I arrived in DC in 1982.
It's just a thing. It's always been. And
this congressman from from New Jersey
wants the secretary of the interior
to take it down by force. There's
another one sort of a sister tent in
front of Union Station, the train
station up on Capitol Hill. Um, and I I
talked to the guy at Union Station last
week. I think I may have mentioned it on
the show. And I asked if he was getting
any push back from from the cops or from
the the Trump people. And he said no. He
said, "Every once a while, somebody will
walk past and give him the finger, but
most people, he said, are very
supportive and pleasant and and say
encouraging things. I walked past the
White House a couple of nights ago on my
way to dinner, and I didn't talk to the
guy that was there, but he was just
sitting in a lawn chair holding a a
Palestinian flag, and people were taking
pictures in front of the tent, and then
taking pictures in front of the White
House. I did notice that Donald Trump
ordered that a giant hole be dug in the
front lawn of the White House. The um
the north the north lawn.
>> I know why.
>> And there's a gigantic flag pole there
now. Cuz we didn't have enough flags
flying from the White House right there
everywhere you look.
>> So now we have this one giant one like a
skyscraper in the center of the of the
White House lawn.
It's just
>> it's going to be hilarious if it if it
falls over during a storm and smashes.
>> Um and that that could happen. Yeah. So,
it's like one of those giant ones like
that you see at the car dealership at
the freeway entrance, right?
>> Yeah. Exactly. Exactly. That's exactly
what it's like. It's a giant car
dealership uh flag.
>> And then, you know, so uh DP has uh this
question. Is this takeover of DC
something like a coup?
Yeah. Well, this is what um Dantis did.
Remember when he took all those uh
wouldbe refugees and put them on a plane
to Massachusetts, right?
>> Which we talked about Martha's Vineyard.
It's kidnapping. It's a federal crime.
But yeah, I think DP's right. How much
you want to bet? I would put money on
the fact that the homeless just get
herded onto buses and dropped off in New
York. I think that's probably what's
going to happen.
>> Yeah. No, it's it's I mean, you know,
and and this is after Mayor Eric Adams
sold out to the Trump administration and
destroyed his chances of re-election.
>> That's right. That is right.
>> So, I think it's I mean, look, I think
that a lot of what Trump does is always
about testing the waters, right? Like he
dips his toe in. Let's see, you know,
what what will happen? Um, you know, can
I get away with this? As you say, I bet
he knows it's three days. Um, you know,
he has lawyers. Uh so he has more
lawyers than God. And so he's got so you
know three he's like well let's see how
let's see how it goes and if that goes
okay then maybe we can do a little more.
You know, there's a there's a story from
uh the Goldfarber, Daniel Goldfar, wrote
this very good book. I'm sure you've
read, John, called Hitler's Willing
Executioners. And um it's very
influential and basically questions the
idea that the that the Holocaust was
basically they put a gun to my head and
then they told me shoot kill the Jewish
guy or I kill you. And he he debunks
that basically. Um and but what's really
amazing that the Holocaust was test
marketed, right? Basically, they tr they
they weren't sure that there wasn't
going to be civil unrest. So, they put
spies in little towns in Poland and in
the cafe at the mayor's office and then
after a big roundup they wanted to see
if there was civil unrest. If there had
been civil unrest, if towns had burned,
if the Gestapo had been attacked, they
were the whole thing was going to be
called off once conference. That was
like part of their deal. But they wanted
to see how it would go. And I think um
you know it obviously not not there were
complaints, nothing much. They were
like, "Oh, this is fine. We can get away
with it." Um I I think that's what Trump
has in mind. In the back of his mind,
he's like, "Let's see, you know, what if
I really did want to seize power, maybe
not have to run for reelection, and I
can't run for reelection, but maybe I'll
just stay in office."
>> Um I think this is a test test. Let's
just see. Well, he said just over the
weekend, Ted, that he his his words
probably won't run for a third term.
>> Probably won't. He cannot. It is written
in stone in the Constitution. There's no
wiggle room. There's no way around it
where he runs for vice president and
then Vance resigns. He can't do it.
>> Wait, he can't do that. He can't run for
vice president and and Vance resigns.
>> No, sir. Or he could run for vice
president and be vice president and if
Vance resigns the the the speaker of the
house becomes president.
>> Really?
>> Yeah.
>> I think it would go I would I think it
would end up tied up in the courts at
that point.
>> Oh, it would definitely be in the
courts. But the constitution's clear
that if the vice president cannot assume
the presidency and in this case he could
not assume the presidency because he's
he's constitutionally barred, then um
then the the speaker of the house
becomes president. Interesting.
Um, well, yeah. I mean, I I've I perhaps
naively have always believed up until
now that the reason he's not uh that he
keeps saying I might run or implies it,
it's just cuz he doesn't want to be a
lame duck because he is a lame duck. And
so,
>> exactly.
>> I think that's all it is. But maybe
right. No, I think you've hit it on the
head. He's trying to remain as relevant
as he can for as long as he can. Now,
that's going to change after the midterm
elections because then that's it. It's
done, right? There are no more
elections. Nobody's going to have to owe
him anything or cowtow to him. All bets
are off
>> unless But then, okay, here's there's
the law of unintended consequences as
always, which we talk about a lot on
this show. So, what if you know he he in
his mind he knows he can't run for
reelection, but you know, he does all
these shenanigans and figures out that
he can get away with it. Then the
thought that he might go back to the
lawfare defendant role that he played
before the sec his second term. The idea
that he might be warming the inside of a
of a prison cell might make him think,
you know, maybe I do want to stay in
office and I might be able to get away
with it. After all, I saw the impetence
of the Democratic Party and of the of
the press and of the non-existent left
in this country. Well, see now that's
that brings us back to the issue that so
many of us struggled with four and a
half years ago was does Trump pardon
himself? It's never been done before.
The Constitution doesn't say anything
about it. So legally, we're unclear as
to whether or not a part a president can
pardon himself, but that could be it.
that that he pretends like he's gonna
run, keeps pretending like he's gonna
run and then pardons himself
>> or however
that doesn't help with the state charges
as we know
>> at all. going after right he's going
after u he the DOJ has just opened an
investigation into a Leticia James
>> uh who went after him with those and she
was viewed as having the most powerful
potent dangerous charges against him.
>> Yeah, thank you Sodon
very much.
>> Let's answer Sodon's question and yeah,
thanks a lot. Um how do you think BB
will be remembered? Gez, especially with
the atrocities against journalists.
>> Clear. Clearly, there are two there are
two answers there.
>> I think he has essentially saved himself
in Israel. As crazy as that sounds,
because this is a guy that has never
ever won more than 27%.
>> But I think in terms of public opinion,
at least right now in Israel, he's saved
himself.
everywhere else in the world. He's going
to go, in my view, he's going to go down
in history with the likes of Paul Pot
and and Edy Amin and uh what's his name?
Pinocha,
some of the the ugliest the darkest
figures of the of the 20th century.
>> Agreed. and he's going to be but I think
in even domestically in Israel once
they've lost the United States and I
think they will
>> I think it'll take a while.
>> Yeah.
>> But it will um then at that point the
Israelis are going to say this is the
guy. It's kind of like the way the
Germans felt about Hitler who' still
supported him but once he led them to
ruin um he this is the guy who ruined
us. Uh we needed the United States. We
couldn't live without them. We already
lost the Democratic Party. Now we've
lost the Republican party as well. We're
screwed and no one's going to run
interference for us at the UN anymore.
>> And that's another thing is this is the
guy who has lost the entire Western
world for Israel. Right? Three weeks
ago,
none of the the important Western
countries
recognize Palestine. And today, all of
the important Western countries with the
exception of the United States recognize
Palestine. So if if you're a thinking
Israeli, you have to say even if you
say, "Oh, I hate Palestinians and we
should be crushing Gaza." You have to
say, "This guy is destroying our
country." But nobody's saying that yet.
I mean, there are a couple of voices on
the Israeli left. You see it in Harets
mostly, sometimes in the Jerusalem Post,
but that's exactly what's happening.
He's destroying Israel.
>> He is. Yeah. I mean, he's he's leading
them completely to total disaster. I
guess we should it seems like a good
time to talk about I mean we're done
with DC but we can always come back to
it. Um but you know let's talk about
these journalists who were killed in
Gaza. I'm absolutely blown away that uh
this time I mean Israel's killed uh you
know up until uh the Gaza war um I was
part of the group of journalists with
the highest fatality rate in the history
of Western war correspondency. I was in
a convoy of 45 journalists um of whom um
you know only uh eight of us sorry 11 of
us didn't come back. That record got
totally destroyed by the Gaza war uh
with the hundreds with hundreds of
journalists deliberately targeted by the
IDF and now and usually they say well we
didn't know they were journalists or
they didn't they weren't wearing their
vest even though they always are. um or
what they didn't have ID. They always
do. But this time there, the IDF is
literally saying this guy was we know
that he we we killed him on purpose
along with four of his colleagues
because he led a Hamas cell. His name is
Anas al- Sharif. Um he's a TV
journalist. If you watch Al Jazer
regularly, you saw him. Um and I mean it
it's like this there's no evidence,
right? Could be true. But if there's
evidence, let's see it. And you know,
nobody ever pushes Israel to put up the
put up our shut up. Um they're but
they're literally saying we reserve the
right to murder journalists on moss. I
mean that's that's a new level. I've
literally you mentioned you mentioned
some desperates. I don't remember Paul
Pot ever arguing that you could do that.
I don't remember Saddam Hussein ever
arguing you could do that. Um you know
it's this is new.
>> You know what? That's an oped right
there. I worked on Iraq for the most
part of 15 years at the CIA through two
wars against Iraq. And Saddam Hussein
hated journalists, but he never went out
and killed them.
>> Benjamin Netanyahu kills them
>> on purpose.
>> On mass.
>> That's right.
>> I mean, he doesn't want because he
doesn't want the truth coming out.
>> That's right.
>> And uh so I mean,
>> you know, I'm I mentioned today I'm
sorry to interrupt you, Ted. I mentioned
today to a friend of mine. I was talking
to a friend of mine today about this and
I said, you know, I'm still livid about
the assassination of of Shireen Abu
Akla. Shireen Abu Akla was at every
event in Washington. She was the top
correspondent for Al Jazzer and she was
at every event
>> and on top of that she was um Greek
Orthodox Christian. She was a Christian
Palestinian. She was in Palestine, what
is it now? Two years ago, I guess. And
she was wearing a bulletproof vest that
said press on it. And she was wearing a
a helmet, a Kevlar helmet that said
press across it. And she was standing
behind a tree to protect herself. And
still an IDF sniper shot her in the face
with a long range high-powered rifle.
And then the Israelis said, "Oh, it was
just a mistake." Um, they thought she
was Hamas. No, she was wearing press
press gear. And then the Israelis said,
"Oh, no, no, no. She was she was
collaborating with Hamas." And then the
response was, "No, she was the most
important, most prominent, most famous
journalist that that uh that Al Jazzer
had and a Christian on top of it all."
And what did the Israelis do? Her
funeral was held in a Greek Orthodox
church in the West Bank. The Israelis
forced their way into the church. In the
midst of the funeral, beat the
pawbearers with trenchons and they were
they were forced to drop the coffin
which opened and then revealed her body.
It was it was solely to humiliate and to
anger. And then BB says, "Well, we'll do
an investigation. We'll get back to
you."
Now, they don't even bother now. They
just kill the whole group. It's a It's a
an Alazer journalist and and four uh
cameramen and producers. Just kill
everybody because what's going to
happen? They know nothing's going to
happen. The Americans aren't going to
say anything. Nothing ever does. And the
Americans aren't going to say a single
word.
>> Not a word.
>> John, we have an ad. I'm going to read
it through very quickly.
>> Oh, good for us.
>> You're You've probably noticed Rumble is
growing fast and it's not slowing down.
They're building a real alternative to
big tech that puts creators first but
actually protects free speech. And now
there's Rumble Premium, an easy way to
upgrade your experience with Premium.
You get ad free viewing across the
platform. No pre-rolls, no
interruptions, just the content you came
for. Plus, premium members unlock
exclusive content like bonus videos,
behind the scenes drops, and more from
your favorite creators. Right now,
Rumble's offering 10 bucks off an annual
subscription. Just go to
rumble.com/premium and use the promo
code studio at checkout. That's
rumble.com/premium promo code studio. No
ads, more free freedom and content you
actually care about. That's the deal.
Um, thank you for the ad. I mean, you
know, the fact that we have the ads is a
sign that we are becoming a bigger a
bigger show and more successful. Uh, we,
you know, we wouldn't have that ad if we
wasn't thanks to you guys listening. Um,
if you haven't gotten the message before
about how we make a lot more money if
you watch us on Rumble, um, we make a
lot more money if you watch us on
Rumble. So, uh, if please do, it really
makes a huge difference. And when I mean
a lot more money, I don't mean like
instead of two cents, we get two and a
half cents, right? Uh, it's like instead
of two cents, we get like a dollar. So,
>> right.
>> It's like it's exponentially more money.
It is crazy.
>> I actually didn't believe it when Robbie
explained it to us.
>> No, it's so extreme. Like if you really
want to support the show and you get the
same exact experience. And by the way,
if you think that Rumble is sketch or
whatever because it's got a lot of
right-wing content, there's a $5 option
instead of a 10 $10 option gets you
everything. The $5 option gets you uh
you can just watch our show and not
watch anything else just cart on Rumble.
So, which is kind of a good a positive
change that they've made. Um all right.
So, with that, um
>> may may I interrupt Ted,
>> please? a couple of interesting and I
think important uh comments. I want to
go back uh to uh let's see.
Oh, I'm going to I'm I'm going to find
it. But anyway, uh we've got a couple.
Uh Rid, was Michael Hayden a good CIA
director? One of the worst CIA directors
in American history. He was the one that
um that uh not only gave us warrantless
wiretapping when he was director of the
of the NSA. When he went to CIA, he ran
the torture program and the rendition
program and the secret prisons program.
And when he was called out on it,
actually doubled down and co-authored a
book on why torture was good. Number
one, um, MW, excuse me, MW Knox 186,
America sells out Middle Eastern
Christians, but instead of 30 pieces of
silver, we get $37 trillion of debt. I
wish I had thought of that. I wish I had
thought to say that.
>> So, yeah, because that is 100% that's
exactly what's happening.
>> And we have sold out Middle Eastern
Christian.
>> I miss our pope. Um, you know, the last
pope right now would be raging over what
the Israelis did to the uh that
historical Catholic church.
>> Yeah. In Gaza.
>> He blew up. I mean, the Israelis blew
up, not the pope.
>> And the same thing with the Greek
church, St. Porfidios early on in in
October or November uh two years ago,
they they bombed St. Portfidio's church,
which was the longest continuously
active church in the world from the
600s. It's been open like every Sunday
for since the 600s. Not only did the
Israelis bomb it and destroy it, but
they killed 24 women and children that
had taken refuge inside. Unforgivable.
>> And they and the thing is they have the
tech. They know there there's no fog of
war really in this situation. I mean no
>> that like you know in the case that you
talked about like with the sniper that
guy had a clear field of vision. They
have inc you know it's the weather is
always really crystal clear. It hardly
rains over there. I mean it's there's no
excuses. They're doing it on purpose. I
just want to be
>> Yes indeed.
>> Yes. St. Nicholas on 911. It's been
rebuilt at the 911 footprint and it is
absolutely magnificent. You should check
it out.
>> Yep. Yep. That's that's true. Um, okay.
So, by the way, I remember Michael
Hayden, you know, he back be this was
back I guess in the was it the '9s when
he was at NSA?
>> He started in 98 or 99. Yes. There was
an article in the French magazine novel
El Zato where he was quoted talking
about uh mass surveillance and he was
bragging at the time openly that the US
could and did listen and store every
conversation every form of communication
at the time things that we forgotten
about like TX and stuff like that but
you know basically every email
everything
>> everything every text message every
voicemail every email every bit of
metadata for the next 500 years
>> all stored and like I loved I love the
sophistry that they said they said as
far as they're concerned it's not really
intercepted until someone actually at
NSA goes and listens to it. So in other
words I can record you nude taking a
shower and but I I haven't really
recorded it until I go to watch it. I
just have it on my shelf. What nonsense.
>> I mean, that's like, so if I have the
Beatles White album, but I don't ever
listen to it. Do I have the Beatles
White album? Really? I'd say yes. I'd
say yes, I do.
>> I tell you what, in in 2008, this is
right after I blew the whistle in the
torture program, but before my arrest, I
was invited to be on uh Bill Maher's
show. I forget the name of it. Whatever.
Bill Maher show.
>> Real time. Terrible name. Terrible.
>> Terrible. A terrible show.
>> Terrible show. So, um, so I was going to
be on with, um, with Mike Hayden and
we go I I flew out there. He flew out
there and in the green room, we're
sitting there and I I said, "Hi, Mike."
And he said, "General Hayden." I said,
"I'm not in the military, Mike." And I
realized, of course, instantly that it
it bothered him very much that I wasn't
calling him General Hayden. And I
refused. And he walked out. He walked
out of the show and I was on by myself.
>> What a puss.
>> Yeah, that's how he is. And I went to an
event recently at the National Press
Club that was sponsored by the Michael
Hayden Center for the Study of
Intelligence at George Mason University.
And he's had a number of uh of strokes.
And I don't I don't wish them this on
anybody, but um he got up to thank
everybody. He has two canes. And there's
this young woman who physically lifts
him up out of the chair cuz he couldn't
get up himself. And he's bent over
balancing on the two canes like this.
And he opens his mouth and like this
drool comes out of his mouth and goes
all the way to the floor and he just
says, "Thank you. Thank you." And then
he sat down. And I was like, "Okay, well
there, but for the grace of God."
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> He got what he had coming.
>> At that point, you're sort of like,
"Okay, karma caught up." Um, Michael
Hicks uh is saying on YouTube, "John, my
mom says that you became that you become
what you don't forgive." It seems clear
to me that Israel hasn't forgiven being
rounded up into ethnic ghettos.
>> Oh, isn't that by a militarized state
>> and that is you've hit the nail right on
the head there. That's I wish I had
thought of that to say that.
>> Well, I mean it's right. It's like the
it's the it's the trauma thing, right?
Like if I mean it's like if my mom used
to hit me so if I were to hit my kid I
would be justified. I don't think so.
But that is often how it works. Um and
you know I mean certainly uh there's a
whole field of psychology that could be
applied toward nation states and their
policies.
>> Oh imagine imagine how many PhD
candidates are thinking about this
dissertation right now. What we're
seeing unfolding in Gaza and and how to
make psychological sense of it. Totally.
Well, yeah. I mean, you know, it's like
when you're um I think when you're
belleaguered and you feel victimized,
then you justify you can easily justify
anything to yourself and you know, like
and and that's what's happening, right?
I mean, everybody just says October 7th,
October 7th, we can do anything we want.
>> And it's like, okay, so you're allowed,
first of all, there's you don't
necessarily have to react at all, but
how you react is up to you. You know,
it's it's this is it's those are the
words of the abuser. Well, October 7th,
so we can do anything we want. We can
drop an atomic bomb on on Gaza City. We
can do anything. October 7th, we can we
can kill all the babies and eat them.
October 7th, you know, anything we want.
Anything. I mean, it's it's absurd
really. But it's also
>> I went I went to an event the other day.
Um it was it was a conservative event
and I don't even know why I went just
because I was invited. So I I went and
there was this idiot there. He was the
head of the Iowa Republican party. And
he's one of these abortion absolutists
that,
>> you know, not only should all abortions
be illegal from the moment of
conception, but if a woman miscarries,
she should be investigated and, you
know, all that stuff. And he said
something about Gaza. I don't even
remember what it was. And I said, you
know, it's up to all of us to support
human rights. I said, "This is the thing
I don't understand about you, you
so-called pro-life absolutists. You guys
are pro-life from the point of
conception to the point of birth, and
then you don't give a [__] what anybody
does or has happened to them once
they're once they're born." And he says
to me, "You sound like you're pro-
Hamas."
And I said, "You see, that's what I
mean." I said, "You're a [__] idiot,
and there's nothing I can do with that."
>> And that's how I left it.
>> Yeah. No. No. Well, that that's
>> I blocked his phone number. He had given
me his phone number earlier in the day
and I blocked it.
>> Yeah. No, no. I mean, I I hear a lot of
that kind of thing. And you know, I
mean, well, you know, the the thing is
that Israelis, right, they have the term
for this um you know, this form of of
arguing and it's called haz, right? It's
basically like, you know, we we get our
we're going to say whatever it takes,
facts be damned, just to get our way.
We're going to bully you, yell at you,
shout at you. It's like, you know, if
you've ever seen uh either a reenactment
or footage of a cultural revolution
struggle session where some poor sap's
wearing a dunce hat, it's 1968, the
whole and and he's got like a a sandwich
board with all of his purported sins
like I was a member of the of the of the
landlord class or whatever. And the
entire village is screaming at him to re
that he's a capitalist dog running dog
that he's, you know, he betrayed the
masses and the revolution. Uh he's an
enemy of Mao. Everyone's throwing like
rotten fruit at him. And it's like, of
course, most people, almost everyone,
they're just going to break down. And
that's like what it's like online. these
I mean the IDF hires they have thousands
of people employed all over the world
just to go to for example the comment
section of
>> yeah not this show but they they're
going to come here
>> oh they'll come here
>> they they're on they're on uh my comment
sections wherever my cartoons appear
I've got a kind of a barn burner of a
cartoon about Gaza up right now and
they're those people are way up my ass
right today over that and it's like you
know it's it's it's cyber warfare And
you know the thing is there is no point
really engaging with them or talking to
them cuz like with normal people if you
present them with facts like let's say
you know that I'm a liberal I was always
supportive of Israel and then someone's
like well but then look they did this
they did that eventually you can wear
them down you know like the water making
the going the Colorado River you know
carving out the Grand Canyon but that's
like not but you can't you know it but
you can't do that with these people
because they're not trying to have a
discussion. It's like they're trying to
just browbeat you to death.
>> That is absolutely right. Hey, Cameron
Dley asks a good question. What's it
like when you're on those Pierce Morgan
debates? How do you try and make a point
while being cut off so often? Thank you.
Thank you for that. Um,
you know, I I gave it back to Alan
Dersitz as as best I could. Um, and the
other couple of times I was on once with
Scott Horton, who I love and have great
respect for, and and Scott was the one
doing the attacking against the other
guys. Uh, and then the last time I was
on
Oh, yeah. That was a weird experience
because I was I was on with Jack Pobiac
and um, you know, I always considered
him to be if not Satan and one of
Satan's relatives. And then I'm we're
we're 10 minutes into it and I realized,
oh my god, they have me here to be on
Jack Pobiac's side because what it ended
up being was about Gaza.
And I said, you know, these
evangelicals,
they're perfectly happy to watch the
Israelis just bomb any Christian church
they want and wipe out entire Christian
villages. And everybody's perfectly fine
with that because they think that if
they force all the Jews back to Israel
that Christ is coming and they're all
going to go up in their rapture, which
of course is nonsense and not mentioned
anywhere at all in the Bible. It's a
late 19th century invention of the
American Southern Baptist Church. So,
um, you know, I I the way I was raised
was to not interrupt or to apologize for
interrupting and to try to wait my turn
and and be helpful. And I really try
hard to do that. Um, that has to go out
the window on Pierce Morgan because he
expects you to jump in. In fact, his
producer told me not to be afraid to
interrupt, that if the interrupting gets
to be too much that PICE will break it
up. But, uh, it's not really in my
nature to interrupt. I I have to force
myself to do it on that show. Thanks for
asking that. That was a funny question.
>> Yeah. Yeah. No, it's uh it is it's uh
you know there's a lot of these shows
they kind of feel beers Morgan I've
never been on but it doesn't seem like
it's like quite like this but I remember
I was a regular on Fox in like the uh
about 20 years ago all the time over war
on terror stuff and they had ergonomic
warfare like so like you'd go in and
like if you were on bill on the O'Reilly
factor or whatever you were sitting on
like a broken secretar's chair that was
like you had a hard time like
maintaining your balance. You're you're
about a foot below Bill and you know I'm
6'2 so I'm not really used to that
looking up like this and the and and
Bill is just sitting at a nice
comfortable Aeron chair leaning up
against the table and you're sitting
there like and it's like they do
everything to to [__] with you. The
cameraman literally would be like
whispering like comments like at you
like while you're on on the air and he'd
be like, you know, like
>> come on. Oh, come on.
>> It was I mean it was it was like being
razed like you know by a by a baseball
catcher, you know? I mean it's like and
I was just like this is so immature and
I was like look I was bullied throughout
my childhood. you can't do anything to
me. I'm like, you know, you can't it's
not gonna do anything to me, but it must
work with some people. One time I saw uh
Hannity was doing that to someone and
they brought in this like English
professor from, you know, Oxford or
something and she obviously had no idea
what Fox was. And so, you know, he
starts yelling at her like, you know,
why are you with the terrorists? She's
like, pardon me, I don't.
At one point, she's like very
thoughtful. She's like, "I'm sorry. Is
there something wrong with the
connection? Why are you shouting at me?"
>> Good for her. Good.
>> But she was genuinely puzzled and it was
kind of a superpower to watch
>> that dog on Bill O'Reilly. I think I
mentioned to you his producer called me
once to get me on the show and I said,
"Sure, I'll come on the show." And he
said, "Well, you're not allowed to go on
any show three days before or three days
after our show." I said, "Get out of
here. I'm not going to just block off a
week to be on the Bill O'Reilly show.
So, I said, "No,
>> a week."
>> And then they called later like, "Well,
you know, we could make it two days and
two days, but I said, "No, I'm not doing
it." And I didn't. I never went on his
show.
>> Not doing it.
>> All the time. I mean, the first time I
went on, my friend said in who was a DC
insider, uh, you know, his, uh, his his
girlfriend at the time was Laura Bush's
PR flag,
>> and she and he and he said like, "And if
you go on the factor and you survive,
you've won
>> and they and it's true. They cut your
mic constantly. I think you're making a
point. I
>> heard that."
>> Yeah. And like, you know, you don't get
it out. It's It's pretty bad. That's at
a certain point why liber you know
liberals will not go on or lefties or
progressives just because you get
abused. It's not like I don't think it's
not even that they're not asking or that
people are afraid. It's just not worth
it.
>> Uh do you prep for those shows and do
some research beforehand or do you just
wing it? What do you do Ted?
>> Oh I Well, it depends on the topic. I
mean if it's something I know a lot
about like the back of my hand I just
show up. Um but you know let's say it's
about editorial cartooning or whatever
right but if it's about something
complicated um you know something invol
or a fastm moving story like for example
if we're talking about DC it was going
to be 500 national guardsmen then a
couple hours later it's 800 national
guardsmen so I feel like you just want
to be up to date in case those details
come up. What about you John? Um, I
almost never prepare because I figure if
I don't know these issues by now, I'm
never going to know them. Um, although
I'm giving a speech in New York on
Saturday at a hackers convention and um,
I'm not a hacker and tech is not my
strong suit necessarily. So, I'm I'm
preparing for this one, but only to make
references to like Vault 7 and stuff
that the CIA has been doing. But yeah,
otherwise, no, I don't uh I don't
prepare.
>> I And I do think that like having things
that are like read through or being
overprepared can really screw you up
like in a public appearance. Um I have a
friend, she's a she's a brilliant
cartoonist. Uh and but she like reads a
speech. And I'm like, that's like death.
Don't do that.
>> Show up with some bullet points that you
want to talk about ju if you need a card
to remind you, great. But just know the
topics. You know,
>> one one of the guys at the uh at the
speakers bureau that I had signed with a
while ago said that that I did the Trump
weave. Like I'd start one story and then
take a side road into another story and
I end up coming out, you know,
completing the story, but I do the
weave. And it's because I don't write
anything down. I just I just walk up to
the podium and start talking.
>> Well, I mean, there's a lot to be said
for that. I mean, it's a lot more
entertaining and that is what Trump does
and I think it's part of the reason that
he beat Hillary Clinton. Hillary Clint
the the stump speech is dead. Someone
needs to tell the Democratic party. Uh,
you know, no one should go from town to
town giving the same exact speech. You
should go and have one thing to say and
it should sound natural. People don't
want that anymore.
>> That's true. That's absolutely right.
>> Got a question here that I want to
answer. Uh Cameron Dally is asking,
"Ted, is political cartooning dying? Who
do you still respect in the field?" Um
it's absolutely dying. Um I I would say
it's dead. Uh when I got into this um in
the early 90s, I was syndicated in 1991.
There were,200 full-time editorial
cartoonists in the United States.
>> 12 there are eight.
>> Okay. So, uh it is it's finished. Um,
there are, you know, 20 or 30 sort of
freelancers who, you know, they they get
some their work out there here and
there. Uh, but really that's about it. I
mean, Joel Pet still doing good work.
Um, I I like Jack Omen's work. Um,
there's a there's a lot of several
others. Um, you know, uh, Galler just
got got fired from the Baltimore Sun.
He's good. But I mean the thing is and
the cartoonist who I look at though who
is the guy who I'm like that guy's
smarter than me and I wish I was as good
as him is uh Ruben Bowling. His real
name is Ken Fischer. He does a comic
called Tom the Dancing Bug and it is
always so damn smart and I'm like I hate
you.
>> How how about Tom tomorrow? Do you read
him?
>> I I used to um you know we were both in
a lot of the same papers together. In
fact, we both used to get confused for
each other because Ted R, Tom tomorrow,
we both worked in four panel format,
black and white, both progressive um and
uh yeah, so of course obviously um he's
a a very important cartoonist. I always
thought he was too wordy and um I always
thought and I I never really liked the
look of it and after a certain time so
what the thing about for me the judge is
am I going to be surprised like like if
with Ken with Ruben Bowling I never know
what he's going to do and there's
probably going to be something funny and
crazy in it. That's the judgment for me.
Um you know but like Tom tomorrow I feel
like if I miss it
no big deal.
Dan, if you're watching, that's his real
name.
>> I love it.
>> Sorry.
>> I love it. He used to write to me when I
was in prison and and he did a he did a
comic about me and then he he sent me a
copy which was very generous. I have it
framed in my den.
>> He is a Yeah. No, he's a he is a nice
guy. Um you know, and it's many times I
always thought like, well, we might
become friends and hang out and then we
just never do. It's like unrequited
friendship, you know, like the bromance,
the one-way bromance,
>> right? But you know, yeah, he's like one
year older than me, I think. And uh
>> you know, yeah, and um yeah, this modern
world is that's right is his name.
>> This world love it.
>> Get your war on is David Reese. Uh he
that that stopped a long time ago. It
was clip art comic that you get
criticized not by me uh about that fact,
but uh it was a very classic Bush
administration era. If you really are
interested in those kind of comics, I
edited this series of books called
Attitude and uh basically they're
interviews and sample cartoons and with
alternative like weekly cartoonists.
It's from 2002 04 and six and you can
get them on eBay for very little and
anyway they're you can get a really good
sense of the kind of stuff that I like
and the kind of people that I like.
>> Excellent.
>> Where where did we meet Ted? We met uh
when you came on the show that Brian
Becker and I um were doing in 2017.
>> That's right.
>> Yeah,
>> that is co that's that's right. Yeah. Um
yeah. And Brian's still going strong,
right?
>> Going strong with with the socialist
program. You know, I pointed Brian as an
example of what I I hope we can
accomplish all the time. I ran into
Brian. Well, it's been a little while
now. It uh February was the last time I
saw him. He spent so much time in New
York. I don't get to see him much in
Washington anymore. I saw him at a at a
counter inauguration event
>> um with Angela Davis and a couple of
other people and he's doing very very
well with his podcast. He when when we
lost our jobs at um actually
I had left Sputnik briefly. I end up
going back, but when our show was shut
down at Sputnik back in 2020, he did a a
GoFundMe to raise five grand just for
some sound equipment, a decent camera,
and a microphone. And that's how he
started the socialist program. And now
he's a monster. He's he's making more
money than he's ever made in his life.
>> That's so great. Ironically, considering
the
>> He's a communist. Yeah.
>> So, we've got like a couple of questions
over from the Rumble feed. We don't want
to feel like you guys are left out.
>> Absolutely. So, uh, um, rebellious
rainbow unicorn wants to know, is Ali
Mortata still alive?
I don't know who that is. Do you?
>> No, I sure don't.
>> So, okay, someone needs to chime in.
>> I apologize.
>> And another And then, uh, uh, Apac test
dummy. Love that name. Was October 7th
enabled by Israel so they could light a
backfire to Gaza and Iran? I think
there's something there. I think it was.
They knew it was 100% they knew it was
coming.
>> I agree.
>> Um, you know, the they had all, you
know, the the the Hamas posted the um
the the the the the videos of them
practicing like months ahead of time on
the internet.
>> So, I mean, unless the MSAD doesn't look
at at Facebook um or or X, I don't think
that they could have missed it or
Instagram. And then when it happened,
and this blows me away, and you probably
shouldn't just take my word for it, but
go look at the New York Times or the
Washington Post on October 7th there.
The response time to some of these
kabutsum was 7 and a half hours. Now,
there's no place in Israel that is so
that is seven and a half hours away from
any other place in Israel. Um, it is a
small country. You can drive with
traffic four hours maybe from the long
from, you know, diagonally across from
one corner to another. It's not it's the
size of New Jersey. And so,
>> you know, seven and a half hours tells
me
>> they didn't want to come. Also, there
was a smart fence, John. I mean, so
what's the purpose of a smart fence? It
was like if you have a it's like if you
have a regular alarm system in your
house and you know the little and
someone breaks the window. Well, the
little electric thing gets broken and it
calls your local police department and
sets off an alarm. The cops know
instantaneously that your window's been
broken and they can come out right away
if they want. Well, if they want the the
smart fence was breached by Hamas on
October 7th. They didn't come. They
didn't come. So, they knew it was
coming. They were like, I don't think
they told Hamas to do it. I don't think
they planned it, but I think they were
like, "This is going to be our great
opportunity to build greater Israel and
annex."
>> That was it. First of all, thank you,
John Magcguire, very much for that.
Appreciate your generosity. Um, Ted, I
couldn't agree more. And remember this
this weak half excuse that came out from
the Israeli government uh in the days
after uh October the 7th. Uh the excuse
was that well we knew something was
coming but Smotri and Bengir told us it
was going to be in the West Bank. We
didn't know it was going to come from
Gaza. We know that's not true because
settlers along the line with Gaza were
reporting for months that there was
training underway. And then remember in
the days before
uh uh October 7th, Hamas sent balloons
over as a test
>> and still the Israeli the Israelis did
nothing. So that tells me that of course
the Israelis knew it was coming. Um and
why would they want it to happen? so
that they could launch their drive for
greater Israel. Yes,
>> I'm 100% convinced. Couple of qu
questions. Instead of printing news
publications with cartoons, there should
be a publication of only cartoons. I bet
it would sell. It's been tried a few
times. Um, there was something called
Comic Relief, which ran for a number of
years. It was really good. Um, it was
cartoons only. There's the Santa Cruz
Comic News, which probably still is in
business out in California. Um, and
today there's still a longunning
publication called Funny Times, um, out
of Cleveland, Ohio. But it's not enough.
I mean, the reason these places survive
is because they only pay reprint fees.
And if you want a professional
cartoonist, someone who gets up in the
morning and basically lives and breathes
and thinks about cartoons every day and
produces a cartoon like close to every
day or every day, that's not going to do
it. So, I mean, the real answer in my
opinion is to convince news uh online
websites like CNN.com, MSNBC.com,
Axios.com, and all these places that are
basically the successors to legacy media
to start running cartoons and not just
political cartoons. Um Cameron wants to
know, "How do we get how do journalists
get into a war zone? What's the
preparation like?"
>> Oh, it's different from the way I got
in. I got in business class.
>> Yeah, it's not the same. So, so
technically, I mean, it's pretty funny.
you you're basically going it depends.
You try to get permission as much as you
can, but sometimes you can't. So, for
example, I I covered the 2014 um Israeli
invasion of Gaza, right? And um to get
in there um I I was like I first went I
looked into whether you could go in
through Israel. The border was closed
and the Israelis wouldn't give you any
permission. But then I was like, Egypt,
go through the tunnels. Um, and so I
crossed I Egypt was easy to get into,
but then arriving in on the Hamas side,
you have I didn't have a visa. Hamas
does issue visas or at least they used
to.
>> What
>> always fun to get that stamp that
attracts all sorts of attention in
interesting places. So back it was a
government you know and so but I got
Hamas to but I arrived I I explained
myself obviously I wasn't the only media
person but they check you out too like
who are you online and oh okay this guy
is legit he's okay and then they let you
in. So it always depends Afghanistan was
this is a good story. So, in 2001, I was
dying to get over there right away. Um,
you know, after the bomb started falling
on October 4th, and I went all over the
place to people who didn't have anyone
there, various TV stations, networks,
um, newspapers, and they were and I got
turned down for a variety of reasons.
And finally, I was like, I went to the
Village Voice where I was on staff and I
was like, "Guys, you know, I'll put I'll
cobble it together. I'll do like a
little bit of radio with KFI radio and
send me over there. They're like, "No,
we have a guy. He's going in um he's in
he's on a he's on a uh he's on a US Navy
uh battleship in the in the Indian
Ocean." And I'm like, "You're aware of
the fact that Afghanistan is a
landlocked country, right? Like you your
guy's in a nav is on a naval vessel.
He's not going in." He's like, "Oh,
really? You think you know better?" I'm
like, "I know I know better." And so
then they they were like, "Okay, well,
never mind, Ted. We have another guy.
He's going to go in through Pakistan um
through the Kyber Pass. And I'm like the
first thing the Pakistanis do when
there's trouble is they shut that Kyber
Pass. No one's going in there. So I'm
like to Jikstan is the way. So like I
flew to I convince them. They're like
okay you want to take your shot. I flew
to Duchon Bay but it's basically all
catches catch can. You arrive there. You
have to get a special permission from
the Taji government as you find out to
go to the trouble zone which is a 100
kilometers away from the Afghan border.
Then you have to figure out how to get
how to cross that border. Are you I was
going to take a chopper. Now the
chopper's not flying because it's uh
which was going to the northern alliance
capital of um that chopper wasn't going
because of fog in the in the mountains.
So then you just like okay it will go by
go over land. Gotta hire got to hire
someone to go over land. Then you have
to get So you basically you're bringing
tons and tons of cash and that's the
most nerve-wracking part. Yeah. Because
you're walking around with at least 50
to $100,000 in $100 bills in a place
where $20 is a life-changing amount of
money. So you're an you're a walking ATM
in a place where everyone's got guns and
and they're desperate and they're hungry
and they're pissed off. Um, so, so yeah,
it's like basically
>> and you don't know if they're g, you
don't know if they are willing to let
you bribe them for $20 or if they're
going to kill you for the whole 50.
>> No, that's right. That's exactly right.
You don't know anything that's going to
happen. I can't tell you how many times
I had to talk my way out of being
murdered. you you sort of lose track
after a while and you're like quoting
from the Quran and you're like you know
you offer you know the Quran requires
you as a good Muslim to give sanctuary
to the unarmed traveler and then like
are you Jewish or are you a good Muslim
and they're like hey u I'm a good Muslim
really because you're acting like a Jew
and then like I mean you say anything
that it you need to get through a
situation like that but then there's
hotel wars which are like Like Bosnia,
it was a hotel war. You know, you stayed
at like a nice hotel, drive out to the
front, make it back to the hotel by
happy hour, easy peasy. Three, three,
four stars. So, just it really really
depends. You could do a whole show just
on that,
>> man. That's a rough life.
>> And and I think I'm too old for it, you
I mean, I realized when I was in my 50s,
like you don't really you can't you're
not going to have the instincts for it
>> um once you get over like say 52, 53.
>> Yeah, that's a tough life.
>> All right, so um Ali Mart Mortada, his
famous greeting, hello my enemies. He
was pretty funny. Oh, is he Oh, is he
the comedian, the stand-up comic guy?
Oh, Oddball Comic. Okay. So, thank you
John Maguire for your generous donation.
Oddball cartoon question. Have you ever
put one of your question cartoons into
the new AI image
>> to video creators to see what it does to
it? Yes, I have.
>> Ah,
>> and uh it does.
>> Does it steal it from you?
>> It probably it tried. So, I have a very
simple drawing style and one of the
things that nobody knows is that simple
drawing styles are harder to replicate
than complicated drawing styles. So
because like if you just think about
like Charlie Brown, there's like maybe
seven or eight lines that make Charlie
Brown's face. Those each line has to be
really perfect otherwise the whole
thing's [__] up. But if you draw
something that's like full of
cross-hatching like the sort of the
mistakes can cancel each other out. So
AI is like very simplistic and it
doesn't know what to do and it doesn't
get the lines right. So it basically
there's no other way to put it. It looks
makes it look like a retard's been
drawing it. Um, and so
>> that's great.
>> Everything's off and weird. It's gonna
get better.
>> And I'm I'm dying for it to get better.
I want to use it to be able to produce a
cartoon like 5 seconds after I hear
about a new story and get it out there
right away because that does better. Um,
I'm not at all against new technology.
Um, you know, because it's going to
happen whether I'm against it or not.
>> Yeah, I think you're right.
>> Oh, uh, this I'm sure is, uh, well, it
might be for either of us. I was not at
the Battle of Tora Bora. How were you?
No, I arrived 2 months after Tora, but
that's that's why I went. I went to
clean up the remnants of Tora Bora and
and we had some real success.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, just as an aside,
>> cleaning up, you mean you're scavenging
for evidence and information and stuff
that's left behind
>> and grabbing people that were a little
too slow to get away from us? I I I have
a uh you know what? I I'll bring it for
the for the next uh show. I have a giant
chunk of raw lapis lazuli
>> that I took from Osama bin Laden's
house.
>> I like to think it was his paper weight.
>> It probably was.
>> I think it probably was, but I I took it
and I I still have it. It's magnificent.
>> Do you have any of his videos?
Apparently had quite the video.
>> No, but you know what though? I I went
on a show. I I I never say no to to
reporters from Pittsburgh, right? So, I
went on KDKA TV2. They have a local Meet
the Press after the National Meet the
Press. So, it's it's the it's
uh what was his name?
I forget his name. Anyway, he was the
the host and um and the editor-inchief
of the Pittsburgh Post Gazette was the
other was the other questioner. And so
the Meet the Press guy, I mean the uh
the Pittsburgh Post Gazette guy was not
the friendliest guy in the world. And he
used to kind of zing me every once in a
while. So he said to me, "How surprised
were you that there was so much porn on
Osama bin Laden's computers
and I think he wanted to make me blush
or whatever." And I said, "Oh, you know,
it's funny. The night that we killed
him,
>> um a friend of mine from the CIA called
me and said, "How much porn you think is
on that computer?" And I said, "Dude,
are you kidding? It's gonna all be
porn." And then, of course, it was all
porn.
>> A guy with four wives.
>> Yeah. A guy with four wives. And I I
said I said to him, "When you live in
such a repressive culture
>> and you get internet access and nobody
else is in the room, you look at porn."
>> I always say I always say that, right?
You ever notice it's it's in in you know
when there's a sex scandal in Britain,
you know, it's it's never a labor MP
that they find hanging from the ceiling
with a red.
>> So is the Tori
>> always.
>> So they looked at each other and then
and then the one guy says to the other,
>> I think this is the first time that I've
done this show in 25 years that I've
actually been speechless.
>> John got an ad. Quick pause to tell you
about Pickax, the creator and user first
platform built for people, not
algorithms. You know what big tech is up
to. Data mining bot driven feeds.
Blackbox AI deciding who sees your work.
Instead, Pickax hands you an algorithm
free chronicle feed. Chronic
chronological feed with native Rumble
playback. Autopublishing of your live
streams. Free Bluetooth check
verification and full monetization
control. Your voice, your rules. Best of
all, this web version is live right now.
And their iOS and Android apps dropped
next month um on Pickax. Your Rumble
videos play seamlessly right in your
feed as if they were built into the
platform. No embeds, no workarounds,
just smooth native playback. Even
better, in beta now, creators can
connect their Rumble channel to Pickax
to automatically post live streams and
videos so your followers never miss a
moment. You can also write full articles
directly on Pickax today. And later this
year, you'll be able to blast them out
as email newsletters with one click and
build up your own email list for direct
audience access. monetize on your terms
through payw walls, revenue sharing, or
affiliate ads that autoinsert promo
codes and tracking links. And because
bots shouldn't steal your your
spotlight, Pickax hands you a free blue
check so everyone knows it's really you.
Um, uh, Pickax is building tech that
builds up humanity algorithm free, noise
free, human first. Head to pickaxe.com,
sign up, and take your platform to the
next level. Real voices deserve a real
home, by the way. Uh, I'm on it. Um,
okay. So,
>> I you know what? I I am too as of last
night. It's
>> I like it. I like it.
>> Yeah, it's a it's a neat site. Yep. I
agree.
>> Um okay, so let's I got it. We got to
talk about MTG. Um that lady, she's
making some money. So, uh before she
went into Congress not that long ago,
she was her net worth was officially 700
grand. That's basically where Bernie
Sanders was. It's basically like, you
know, one or two nice h one or two
decent houses. Um, ti and uh now she's
her net worth is $22 million. She's had
many many many many stock transactions
before
Trump's tariff pause. She's saying
basically nothing to see here. Shut the
[__] up. Stop talking about this. Go
away. Be quiet. Probably not the best
look for her, but if I were her, I'd
say, "Hey, come and look at my records
if you've got a problem with me.
Otherwise, shut up." I understand she
comes from money, but you know, there
are um there are uh exchangeraded funds,
mutual funds that track, for example,
Nancy Pelosy's investments.
>> Yeah.
>> Which, you know, ought to be
everybody on Capitol Hill should have
blind trusts. Nobody should be actively
investing in anything,
>> right? Or they should be forced to d to
to divest from everything.
>> Yeah.
>> Collect your 0.4% savings interest like
everyone else.
>> Oh, thank you, Star Lion. I appreciate
that. I'm trying my best. You know, Ted
and I both It's This is a tough gig,
especially at our age.
>> It's true. Like, I you know, I feel like
I'm uh trying to reinvent myself.
>> I know, right?
>> I mean, the fun thing is I mean,
actually, I do like it. It's not like
it's an ordeal or anything. I mean, this
is a fun thing to do. I really look
forward to the show.
>> I do, too.
>> Um, so it's it's definitely like a
highlight of my day.
>> Same here. And we're gonna we're going
to be going every day soon.
>> Yeah. Next week.
>> Yeah,
>> that's the plan, right? Um, by the way,
app propo of that. Uh, Wednesday, I'm
traveling back from Montana. So, uh,
we're doing it on Thursday this week.
So, it's Monday, Thursday, Friday this
week. No show on Wednesday. Um, so
that's that. Yeah, J has like five
shows. I have three. Um, the DMZ show
with Scott Stantis is once a week and
then there's the TMI show also. Um,
anyway, uh, so yeah. Uh, she Star Lion
says, uh, never cared about political
cartoons. Still haven't looked into
them, honestly.
Well, that only means that Star Lion's
probably under 60 years of age. Um, I
mean only old people look at them, but
they're such a great format or at least
potentially they can be. Um, anyway, so
MTG, do is there anything to see here
where there's I mean, is there is this
smoke? And if so, is that fire?
>> I I understand that she comes from from
money. So, I don't know. I don't want to
point the finger, but um I will say when
I worked for when I worked for John Ky
and you know how much John Ky has people
mostly from his wife.
>> Well pe people think that and a half or
a little more than half came from his
wife but he was independently wealthy
before her. He um he comes from a very
long line of money. you know, he he
comes off as this as this good Irish
Catholic and um he only discovered that
he was Irish as an adult. His people
came over on the Mayflower. He just
happens to have like one Irish branch of
the family and it just happens to be his
surname. Um but he's worth about 750
million bucks and he didn't give a [__]
what people thought about that. He
didn't care. I I mentioned a couple of
shows ago that um he bought a he bought
a a yacht, but it was it wasn't even a
yacht. It was like this major oceangoing
ship. And to save himself the the yacht
tax, he docked it in Rhode Island
because they don't have a yacht tax in
Rhode Island. They have one in
Massachusetts. And and people just, you
know, practically took to the streets.
We were getting hundreds of calls and
nasty emails and letters. And I said to
the to the staff director, a really good
guy who who actually is a member of the
Kennedy family. Um I said, "You know,
this is a really bad look. The guy's got
all the money in the world. Just pay the
[__] tax."
>> And it took him about two weeks, but he
finally got around to it and he paid the
tax and moved the boat to Massachusetts.
But these rich people, they're all the
same. They're so afraid you're going to
you're going to, you know, chisel $100
from them or something. And God knows
they don't want to pay their taxes.
>> No, that's that that's the thing that
drives them absolutely nuts. Nick's
asking any upcoming guests. Also,
Houdini is asking, "Are we to talk about
Putin?" Yes, we are in about 60 seconds.
Um, so, um, yeah. So guest next
Thursday, I think it is, um I'm not sure
if it's this Thursday or next Thursday,
we've got a a a expert coming in to talk
about sanctions and their uh whether
they're effective or not and what their
actual effect is on civilians um in the
countries upon which they're imposed.
All right, I I think we do need to talk
about Putin and Trump. Um so they're
meeting, I guess, this Friday uh in
Alaska in Anchorage. Um and uh they're
going to be obviously talking about
Ukraine. there's some cons there's some
concern or question as to whether
Zilinski might also be invited to make
it a three-way. Um are you know I mean
um I don't think Zilinsky will get the
invite. I don't think he makes
>> I don't either. It doesn't make any
sense because Trump hasn't had time to
bully him yet,
>> right?
>> What it comes down to is Trump Trump
floated this idea, well if if we let you
just keep all of the Ukrainian territory
that you've seized, is that good enough?
And Putin said yes, apparently.
>> Well, nobody thought to say anything to
Zilinski.
>> Oops.
>> Yeah, but I mean, Ted, we've all said
from the very beginning, we all knew it
was going to turn out this way that the
Russians get Donbass and Crimea,
the the Ukrainians can't join NATO, but
they get a fast track into the EU,
>> and then, you know, we all call it even.
And I'm sorry if you know this is this
is painful and difficult for the
Ukrainians, but the only other choice,
the only alternative is to just keep
fighting the Russians and then you're
going to end up losing your entire
country at the end of day.
>> I mean that is true. And the um yeah I
mean Trump had a funny remark as he
often does uh about Zilinski. He said uh
you know Zilinski says he can't do
anything he can't give up any territory
without getting constitutional approval.
And he's like, but he's like, Zinsky
seems to not need any constitutional
approval to go around killing everybody
and keeping the war going on forever.
>> Fair point.
>> Yeah, I think so, too.
>> I mean, I think Silinsky has led his
country to disaster. Um, you know, I
mean, even if we state if we stipulate
that it, you know, post Meternick in the
era of the nation state that you no
country can invade another country,
>> um, you know, and that that's just
taboo. We can stipulate that, but it
doesn't change the fact that when you
have a very powerful uh and wealthy
neighbor who you uh you know, right next
on your doorstep, you don't [__] with
them, you know. And um you know, it's
like if you're Luxembourg, you don't
tell France to go [__] itself. And
that's what Ukraine did uh to you know,
basically saying we can do whatever we
want. You know, we're going to we're
going to blow up. We're going to kill
Russian minorities in the east. We're
going to join, if we want to join NATO,
we will. Nothing you can do about it.
We're going to depose, you know, the the
Russian friendly president that was
democratically elected and get rid of
him and ask the Americans for help doing
it. I mean,
Putin got pissed off. It's not
surprising.
>> He sure did. He sure did. Thank you, T.
Yeah, Somaliand. Can I talk about Somali
land for a minute?
>> Please do. Please do.
Somali land has been has been seeking
independence and more importantly
recognition for so long. Yeah. 30 years.
30 years they've been looking for
recognition. They have said all the
right things. They have done all the
right things. They have nothing to do
with whatever pseudo government happens
to be in power or quasi power in
Mogadishu. Um the US has met with them
on both official and unofficial bases. I
told you I went to Somali land in uh I
think it was 2011. I went with the
American ambassador in Djibouti, the
defense ates and the director of embassy
security. Um the thing is
that in the White House they're just not
interested in this and it's it's painful
because these people really want to
develop. They really want to do the
right thing. They want to have good
friends and and a steady foreign policy.
And they see that the success that that
the Djiboutins are having in terms of of
building and expanding their port. Uh
they love the fact that there are both
Americans and Chinese there. They really
want to emulate what the Djiboutins have
done
>> and nobody takes them seriously.
>> Let's talk about what's going to happen
at that summit. Um so I mean we know
what Yes, I agree with you. We know
where this war is going to end. The
question is, is it going to be ending
soon? I mean, what is Putin going to be
asking for? What's Trump going to want?
What's going to be the outcome? Is it is
anything significant going to get done,
>> you know, in in one day? I'm curious
about that with these two very
long-winded men. Well, actually, that's
not fair. Trump's not long-winded um in
person, but Putin is. moon is I I can't
imagine that anything that anything
solid uh develops in a day. Somebody
mentioned um Odessa as well. Uh by all
accounts Odessa is safe for the
Ukrainians that the Russians apparently
don't even have designs on it. They just
said that they did in order to to
increase pressure on the Ukrainians. Um
but no, I I don't think anything is
going to be definitively solved,
especially when when half of the waring
parties aren't represented. And so I
think we have to I think what Trump has
to do is get to Putin's bottom line. Now
Trump said something the other day that
he may or may not have made up. And what
it was was that Russia keeps the
territory.
Ukraine joins NATO.
It's like wait a minute Putin's not said
that publicly and you're just announcing
that.
>> That does sound that does sound new.
>> Yeah, it's very new.
>> Putin agreeing to that?
>> No. No, but that's what Trump announced
when he said that he and Putin were
going to meet an anchor jump Friday.
>> I took note of that.
>> So, so I mean would
I think we should train ourselves to not
expect anything.
>> No, agreed. Agreed.
>> There there's going to have to be a
meeting in, you know, Geneva or Vienna
or whatever or Reikuic or whatever.
>> Putin wants I mean Trump wants this done
now.
>> Done.
>> Yesterday.
>> Yes. And I I I don't know if Putin is I
mean he's showing up. It's good that
these two guys are sitting down. I think
in the end they're gonna they're going
to let Zilinsky sit at the kids table
and tell him what's what at the end.
>> I think that is exactly what we should
expect.
>> Um so Houdini is asking if Russia keeps
the territory gained, will there be an
insurgency in those territories?
Certainly not in Crimea.
>> No, certainly not in Crimea.
>> Uh could there be in say the western
part of the Donbos? I doubt
>> you know. I suppose I suppose anything
is possible, but I I I don't see it
happening.
>> No.
>> And then uh
>> it's too heavily Russian.
>> No, I disagree with Eric's saying Trump
just wants a frozen conflict. I totally
disagree with that. Trump wants a peace.
He wants an armistice. He wants a peace
deal. He wants to That's what he gets to
go to Geneva and ask for that for.
>> Um Nick's asking, John, do you think uh
Putin has his eyes on Transnistria? deep
down I think yes but I think that he
realizes it would be full hearty to do
anything about it
>> also you know John Transnistria serves
like an important like function for
smuggling you know it's kind of like
this this no man's land like what
happens in Transnistria stays in
Transnistria everything gets
>> how are you going to get stuff to to
Muldova and to Romania without
transnistria
>> especially with sanctions
>> especially I think I if I were if I were
Putin, I'd leave the Transnistrians
alone.
>> I agree.
>> By the way, they still have a Soviet
flag. How cool is that?
>> Oh my god. Oh my god.
Crazy.
>> Um, Houdini wants to know if they're
meeting, doesn't it mean that a deal was
already made? I'd say that's
>> under normal circumstances. Yes. Under
Donald Trump, I don't think so.
>> No. No. I think they have to sit down
and they do have to do this, you know,
mono ammono.
>> Yeah, they do. Kkefe. Is that a Russian
city?
>> I think it's going to be now, if it
isn't already. It's pretty well split,
but I think it's I think it's
essentially going to be a Russian city.
>> How safe is Putin once the war ends?
He's used the war to get rid of a lot of
oligarchs and powerful government
figures.
>> Yeah,
>> there will be grudges. Russians know
about grudges. They're good at grudges.
They do grudges well.
>> Yeah, that's right.
>> Um, but are they going to try to kill
Putin? I mean, he'd have to be really
weakened before I think he'd be
vulnerable.
>> You know what they say, if you're if
you're gonna kill the king, you better
kill him on the first try.
>> Yeah, that's that's right.
Um,
do you see Russia starting more wars
like after Ukraine, like the left's
narrative says? Absolutely not.
>> No, I don't either.
>> Um,
>> no.
>> Is Macron serious about
No.
you all mailed. Um,
the only way to get to my train.
>> That's interesting. I didn't know that.
>> That's funny. Yeah, I've wanted to go to
the Transnistria. I my my last graphic
novel had an important I studied a lot
about the Transnistria research. Ah,
>> so that's why I know a little bit about
it.
>> Oh, man. All right. So, um,
>> I'm exhausted.
>> I'm exhausted, too. Um, we're going to
cover this. So, on Thursday, we'll be
back to see it'll be the day before the
summit. We'll know a lot more. Well,
certainly, and I guess, um, you know,
that Trump's experiment in direct DC
governance will have come to an
exciting, thrilling conclusion. I hope
there's no rioting or anything between
now and then. If I were
>> I tell you what, I I fear I fear for the
>> days. That's right. I I fear for the
homeless population over these these
coming days. I really do.
>> Oh, a question about your book. What is
your
>> I don't know, man. I
>> I I sent a a threatening email to my
publisher saying it's time to fish or
cut bait. This book was supposed to be
out. I sent them the draft of this book
three years ago. October uh uh April.
Three years ago, April. So, I've had
enough of waiting. I'll I'll let you
know as soon as I hear I'm tired.
>> Um and I think we'll make this the last
question for today. What do we think
about Chetchny's leader at being MIA?
What about the succession with his
teenage son?
>> I don't know anything about it.
>> Um, yeah, Cheschny is like a little it's
like a sort of micro North Korea inside
of the Russian Federation. It's like
very weird.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, you know that I remember reading um,
>> God, what was this book? It was the
history of warfare by John Keegan and
uh, he argued that that the Cheschnians
are the most ferocious warriors on the
planet. completely indomitable, totally
insane.
>> You know, I I met a Russian soldier
once. Where was I?
In was it in Baghdad? Anyway, no, it
wasn't in Baghdad. It was in Manama in
Bahrain. And he told me that the
Chetchins were the only people on earth
that he was afraid of.
>> That's cool.
And okay, well, when we're doing two,
just a reminder, the show goes to five
days a week this coming Monday. So,
>> that's right.
>> Stay tuned.
>> It's going to be fun.
>> Yeah, looking forward to that, guys. You
guys are awesome. Thank you so much.
Please like, follow, and share the show.
Um, we are always appreciative and it
really makes a difference. If you're
watching us on YouTube, please strongly
consider watching us either instead on
Rumble or uh in or supplementally on
Rumble at the same time. makes a huge
difference for us. Thanks so much for
all the donations. Um you can uh John,
do you have a website?
>> I do. It's johncuryaku.com
>> and I'm Tedrall.com. So easy. All right.
U and with that, we're gonna say goodbye
until Thursday. Thank you.
>> Bye everybody.
>> Bye.